Lying is a common behaviour of children, especially  from 5-10 years old. However, parents should notice reasons behind their lies. There are five main reasons:
1.	The looking corner of children is different from the adults’. 
For example, the child says “I have tidied their room”, but it’s still messy. In reality, the child may tidy the room, and that really the truth for them. Similarly, children can really feel that the teacher intends to punish them or copies negatively with them before telling to their parents. 
2.	The education style of parents (over care or too strict) 
Unnecessarily suffocating atmosphere in family can push children to lie to gain more freedom.
3.	The boundary between imagine and truth is not clear. 
Children suppose that if they strongly manifest, a magic can come true. Children say that they get good marks at school, which may indicate that they desire to really done it. Similarly, children talk they do not hit their cousin, which can show their wish that they didn’t do that. This condition will become matter if it maintains after they are 6-7 years old. 
4.	Babies from 4-5 ages can lie to learn to keep their mine for themselves. 
At this period, children realize that surrounding people cannot know exactly what they are thinking. As a result, children lie to try if they can cover their thoughts, or they don’t want the others to know the truth. 
5.	A telling-story children can indicate a baby with a creativity innate.
In this case, children can use the creative ability to escape the unsatisfied reality. They know what they are telling is not the truth, but they hope to rearrange the reality. For instance, some children can imagine that their biological parents were rich and would come and pick them up one day. So, instead of supposing that children lying, adults should consider the reason behind this action, sometimes it is a sign of mental demand. 

In conclusion, parents should not over worry when children lie. Adults sometimes did lie to many reasons. Meanwhile, children tend to follow adults' actions, when they realize the adults are lying to them. In short, parents should make a good model to get the children's belief. 

happy new year!!!

đầu xuân khai code
code khai kim ngân hiihi